<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Research on Yoshiyuki Inoue</title>
    <link>https://yoshiyukiinoue.github.io/tags/research/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Research on Yoshiyuki Inoue</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>ja</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 06 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://yoshiyukiinoue.github.io/tags/research/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Our paper on the possible contributions of blazars to the NGC 4151 neutrino hotspot is accepted by A&amp;A.</title>
      <link>https://yoshiyukiinoue.github.io/post/2025-01-06-ngc4151/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://yoshiyukiinoue.github.io/post/2025-01-06-ngc4151/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Title: &lt;a href=&#34;https://arxiv.org/abs/2411.09332&#34;&gt;On the possible contributions of two nearby blazars to the NGC 4151 neutrino hotspot&#xA;&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;br&gt;&#xA;Authors: Anastasiia Omeliukh, Samuel Barnier, Yoshiyuki Inoue&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The origin of the high-energy astrophysical neutrinos discovered by IceCube remains unclear, with both blazars and Seyfert galaxies emerging as potential sources. Recently, the IceCube Collaboration reported a \UTF{223C}3σ neutrino signal from the direction of a nearby Seyfert galaxy NGC 4151. However, two gamma-ray loud BL Lac objects, 4FGL 1210.3+3928 and 4FGL J1211.6+3901, lie close to NGC 4151, at angular distances of 0.08\UTF{2218} and 0.43\UTF{2218}, respectively. We investigate the potential contribution of these two blazars to the observed neutrino signal from the direction of NGC 4151 and assess their detectability with future neutrino observatories. We model the multi-wavelength spectral energy distributions of both blazars using a self-consistent numerical radiation code, AM3. We calculate their neutrino spectra and compare them to the measured NGC 4151 neutrino spectrum and future neutrino detector sensitivities. Our models predict neutrino emission peaking at \UTF{223C}1017 eV for both blazars, with fluxes of \UTF{223C}10−12 erg cm−2 s−1. This indicates their contribution to the \UTF{223C}10 TeV neutrino signal observed from the direction of NGC 4151 is minor. While detection with current facilities is challenging, both sources should be detectable by future radio-based neutrino telescopes such as IceCube-Gen2&amp;rsquo;s radio array and GRAND, with 4FGL~J1210.3+3928 being the more promising candidate.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Our paper on the Gamma-Ray emission from the nearby Seyfert Galaxy GRS 1734-292 is accepted by ApJ.</title>
      <link>https://yoshiyukiinoue.github.io/post/2025-01-03-grs-1734-292/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://yoshiyukiinoue.github.io/post/2025-01-03-grs-1734-292/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Title: &lt;a href=&#34;https://arxiv.org/abs/2410.02263&#34;&gt;The Disk Wind Contribution to the Gamma-Ray emission from the nearby Seyfert Galaxy GRS 1734-292&#xA;&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;br&gt;&#xA;Authors: Nobuyuki Sakai, Tomoya Yamada, Yoshiyuki Inoue, Ellis R. Owen, Tomonari Michiyama, Ryota Tomaru, Yasushi Fukazawa&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Radio-quiet Seyfert galaxies have been detected in GeV gamma-rays by the Fermi Large Area Telescope (LAT), but the origin of much of this emission is unclear. We consider the nearby example, the Seyfert galaxy GRS 1734-292, which exhibits weak starburst and jet activities that are insufficient to explain the observed gamma-ray flux. With the first detailed multi-wavelength study of this source, we demonstrate that an active galactic nucleus (AGN) disk wind can account for its gamma-ray emission. Using a lepto-hadronic emission model based on a shocked ambient medium and a shocked wind region created by an AGN accretion disk wind, we identify two viable scenarios that are consistent with the Fermi-LAT data and multi-wavelength observations: a hadronic pp-dominated scenario and a leptonic external Compton-dominated scenario. Both of these show that future observations with the Cherenkov Telescope Array (CTA) and the Southern Wide-field Gamma-ray Observatory (SWGO) could detect TeV emission from a disk wind in GRS 1734-292. Such a detection would substantially improve our understanding of cosmic ray acceleration efficiency in AGN disk wind systems, and would establish radio-quiet Seyfert galaxies as cosmic ray accelerators capable of reaching ultra-high energies.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Our paper on the coronal cosmic-ray energy budget in AGNs is accepted by PASJ.</title>
      <link>https://yoshiyukiinoue.github.io/post/2024-06-30-seyfertcr/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 30 Jun 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://yoshiyukiinoue.github.io/post/2024-06-30-seyfertcr/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Title: &lt;a href=&#34;https://arxiv.org/abs/2401.07580&#34;&gt;Upper Limit on the Coronal Cosmic Ray Energy Budget in Seyfert Galaxies&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;br&gt;&#xA;Authors: Yoshiyuki Inoue, Shinsuke Takasao, Dmitry Khangulyan&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The IceCube collaboration has reported possible detections of high-energy neutrinos from nearby Seyfert galaxies. While central hot coronae are proposed as the primary neutrino production site, the exact coronal cosmic-ray energy budget has been loosely constrained. In this study, we propose a new stringent upper bound on the coronal cosmic-ray energy budget of Seyfert galaxies, considering both accretion dynamics and observed properties of radio-quiet Seyfert galaxies. Notably, even under the calorimetric condition where cosmic rays lose all their energies, our limit indicates that the coronal neutrino flux of NGC~1068 is about an order of magnitude fainter than the observed levels. This discrepancy suggests the need for further theoretical and observational investigations on the IceCube signals from Seyfert galaxies.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Our paper on cosmic rays in cosmological filaments is accepted by Universe.</title>
      <link>https://yoshiyukiinoue.github.io/post/2024-06-27-filament/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Jun 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://yoshiyukiinoue.github.io/post/2024-06-27-filament/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Title: &lt;a href=&#34;https://arxiv.org/abs/2407.01208&#34;&gt;Energetic Particles and High-Energy Processes in Cosmological Filaments and Their Astronomical Implications&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;br&gt;&#xA;Authors: Kinwah Wu, Ellis R. Owen, Qin Han, Yoshiyuki Inoue, Lilian Luo&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Large-scale cosmic filaments connect galaxies, clusters and voids. They are permeated by magnetic fields with a variety of topologies. Cosmic rays with energies up to 1020eV can be produced in astrophysical environments associated with star-formation and AGN activities. The fate of these cosmic rays in filaments, which cannot be directly observed on Earth, are rarely studied. We investigate the high-energy processes associated with energetic particles (cosmic rays) in filaments, adopting an ecological approach that includes galaxies, clusters/superclusters and voids as key cosmological structures in the filament ecosystem. We derive the phenomenology for modelling interfaces between filaments and these structures, and investigate how the transfer and fate of energetic cosmic ray protons are affected by the magnetism of the interfaces. We consider different magnetic field configurations in filaments and assess the implications for cosmic ray confinement and survival against hadronic pion-producing and photo-pair interactions. Our analysis shows that the fate of the particles depends on the location of their origin within a filament ecosystem, and that filaments act as &lt;code&gt;highways&#39;, channelling cosmic rays between galaxies, galaxy clusters and superclusters. Filaments can also operate as cosmic &lt;/code&gt;fly paper&amp;rsquo;, capturing cosmic ray protons with energies up to 1018eV from cosmic voids. Our analysis predicts the presence of a population of ∼1012−1016eV cosmic ray protons in filaments and voids accumulated continually over cosmic time. These protons do not suffer significant energy losses through photo-pair or pion-production, nor can they be cooled efficiently. Instead, they form a cosmic ray fossil record of the power generation history of the Universe.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Our paper on cosmic rays in large-scale filaments is accepted by Universe.</title>
      <link>https://yoshiyukiinoue.github.io/post/2024-06-27-filamentcr/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Jun 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://yoshiyukiinoue.github.io/post/2024-06-27-filamentcr/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Title: &lt;a href=&#34;https://arxiv.org/abs/2407.01208&#34;&gt;Energetic particles and high-energy processes in cosmological filaments and their astronomical implications&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;br&gt;&#xA;Authors: Kinwah Wu, Ellis R. Owen, Qin Han, Yoshiyuki Inoue, Lilian Luo&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Large-scale cosmic filaments connect galaxies, clusters and voids. They are permeated by magnetic fields with a variety of topologies. Cosmic rays with energies up to 10^{20} eV can be produced in astrophysical environments associated with star-formation and AGN activities. The fate of these cosmic rays in filaments, which cannot be directly observed on Earth, are rarely studied. We investigate the high-energy processes associated with energetic particles (cosmic rays) in filaments, adopting an ecological approach that includes galaxies, clusters/superclusters and voids as key cosmological structures in the filament ecosystem. We derive the phenomenology for modelling interfaces between filaments and these structures, and investigate how the transfer and fate of energetic cosmic ray protons are affected by the magnetism of the interfaces. We consider different magnetic field configurations in filaments and assess the implications for cosmic ray confinement and survival against hadronic pion-producing and photo-pair interactions. Our analysis shows that the fate of the particles depends on the location of their origin within a filament ecosystem, and that filaments act as &lt;code&gt;highways&#39;, channelling cosmic rays between galaxies, galaxy clusters and superclusters. Filaments can also operate as cosmic &lt;/code&gt;fly paper&amp;rsquo;, capturing cosmic ray protons with energies up to 10^{18} eV from cosmic voids. Our analysis predicts the presence of a population of \UTF{223C}10^{12}−10^{16} eV cosmic ray protons in filaments and voids accumulated continually over cosmic time. These protons do not suffer significant energy losses through photo-pair or pion-production, nor can they be cooled efficiently. Instead, they form a cosmic ray fossil record of the power generation history of the Universe.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Our paper on multi-epoch X-ray spectral analysis of Cen A is accepted by PASJ.</title>
      <link>https://yoshiyukiinoue.github.io/post/2024-06-14-cena/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 14 Jun 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://yoshiyukiinoue.github.io/post/2024-06-14-cena/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Title: &lt;a href=&#34;https://arxiv.org/abs/2406.14488&#34;&gt;Multi-epoch X-ray spectral analysis of Centaurus A: revealing new constraints on iron emission line origins&#xA;&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;br&gt;&#xA;Authors: Toshiya Iwata, Atsushi Tanimoto, Hirokazu Odaka, Aya Bamba, Yoshiyuki Inoue, Kouichi Hagino&#xA;We conduct X-ray reverberation mapping and spectral analysis of the radio galaxy Centaurus A to uncover its central structure. We compare the light curve of the hard X-ray continuum from Swift Burst Alert Telescope observations with that of the Fe Kα fluorescence line, derived from the Nuclear Spectroscopic Telescope Array (NuSTAR), Suzaku, XMM-Newton, and Swift X-ray Telescope observations. The analysis of the light curves suggests that a top-hat transfer function, commonly employed in reverberation mapping studies, is improbable. Instead, the relation between these light curves can be described by a transfer function featuring two components: one with a lag of 0.19+0.10−0.02 pc/c, and another originating at r&amp;gt;1.7 pc that produces an almost constant light curve. Further, we analyze the four-epoch NuSTAR and six-epoch Suzaku spectra, considering the time lag of the reflection component relative to the primary continuum. This spectral analysis supports that the reflecting material is Compton-thin, with NH=3.14+0.44−0.74×1023 cm−2. These results suggest that the Fe Kα emission may originate from Compton-thin circumnuclear material located at sub-parsec scale, likely a dust torus, and materials at a greater distance.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Our paper on radio emission from AGN disk winds is accepted by ApJ.</title>
      <link>https://yoshiyukiinoue.github.io/post/2024-04-02-agnwind/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Apr 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://yoshiyukiinoue.github.io/post/2024-04-02-agnwind/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Title: &lt;a href=&#34;https://arxiv.org/abs/2404.04632&#34;&gt;Deciphering Radio Emissions from Accretion Disk Winds in Radio-Quiet Active Galactic Nuclei&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;br&gt;&#xA;Authors: Tomoya Yamada, Nobuyuki Sakai, Yoshiyuki Inoue, Tomonari Michiyama&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Unraveling the origins of radio emissions from radio-quiet active galactic nuclei (RQ AGNs) remains a pivotal challenge in astrophysics. One potential source of this radiation is the shock interaction between AGN disk winds and the interstellar medium (ISM). To understand this phenomenon, we construct a spherical, one-zone, and self-similar expansion model of shock structure between ultra-fast outflows (UFOs) and the ISM. We then calculate the energy density distribution of non-thermal electrons by solving the transport equation, considering diffusive shock acceleration as the acceleration mechanism and synchrotron and inverse Compton cooling as the cooling mechanisms. Based on the derived energy distribution of non-thermal electrons, we model the radio synchrotron spectrum of shocked ISM. For the 15 nearby RQ AGNs hosting UFOs, we investigate shocked ISM parameters required to model their observed radio spectra, based on X-ray observations and measured UFO velocities. Radio spectra of 11 out of 15 nearby RQ AGNs would be explained by the AGN disk wind model. This is a compelling indication that shock interactions between AGN disk winds and the ISM could indeed be the source of their radio emissions. The typical predicted source size and magnetic field strength are several 100 pc and 0.1 mG, respectively. We also discuss whether our prediction can be tested by future radio observations.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Our paper on Millimeter Time Variability in the Gamma-Ray Detected Seyfert Galaxy GRS 1734-292 is accepted by ApJ.</title>
      <link>https://yoshiyukiinoue.github.io/post/2024-03-01-almavariability/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Mar 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://yoshiyukiinoue.github.io/post/2024-03-01-almavariability/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Title: &lt;a href=&#34;https://arxiv.org/abs/2404.00647&#34;&gt;ALMA Confirmation of Millimeter Time Variability in the Gamma-Ray Detected Seyfert Galaxy GRS 1734-292&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;br&gt;&#xA;Authors: Tomonari Michiyama, Yoshiyuki Inoue, Akihiro Doi, Tomoya Yamada, Yasushi Fukazawa, Hidetoshi Kubo, Samuel Barnier&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;GRS 1734-292 is a radio-quiet galaxy, exhibiting neither intense starburst nor jet activities. However, Fermi-LAT detected this object in the GeV band. The origin of non-thermal activity in this Seyfert galaxy is an intriguing question. We report Atacama Large Millimeter/submillimeter Array (ALMA) observations of GRS 1734-292 at frequencies of 97.5, 145, and 225 GHz. These observations confirmed the millimeter excess within the central &amp;lt;100 pc region and its time variability based on two separate observations conducted four days apart. The timescale of variability aligns with the light crossing time for a compact source smaller than &amp;lt;100 Schwarzschild radius. If we take into account the power-law synchrotron emission originating from the corona (i.e., the hot plasma located above the accretion disk), the millimeter spectrum indicates the coronal magnetic field of ~10 G and the size of ~10 Schwarzschild radius. An alternative explanation for this millimeter emission could be synchrotron and free-free emission from disk winds (i.e., fast wide-opening angle outflows from the disk) with the size of ~10 pc, although it may be difficult to explain the fast variability. Future millimeter observations with higher resolution (~0.01&amp;quot;) will enable the differentiation between these two scenarios. Such observations will provide insights into the acceleration sites of high-energy particles at the core of active galactic nuclei.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Our paper on gamma-ray emission in NGC 4151 is accepted by PASJ.</title>
      <link>https://yoshiyukiinoue.github.io/post/2023-09-29-ngc-4151/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 29 Sep 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://yoshiyukiinoue.github.io/post/2023-09-29-ngc-4151/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Title: &lt;a href=&#34;https://arxiv.org/abs/2304.04138&#34;&gt;Gamma-ray emission in the Seyfert galaxy NGC 4151: Investigating the role of jet and coronal activities&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;br&gt;&#xA;Authors: Yoshiyuki Inoue, Dmitry Khangulyan&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;NGC 4151, a nearby Seyfert galaxy, has recently been reported to emit gamma rays in the GeV range, posing an intriguing astrophysical mystery. The star formation rate of NGC 4151 is too low to explain the observed GeV flux, but the galaxy is known for its coronal activity in X-ray and jet activity in radio. We propose that either the combination of these two activities or the jet activity alone can account for the gamma-ray spectrum. An energy-dependent variability search will allow one to distinguish between the two scenarios, as the coronal component can only contribute at energies of ≲1 GeV. Our analysis also indicates that it might still be difficult to see coronal neutrinos from the apparently X-ray brightest Seyfert NGC 4151 with current-generation neutrino observatories.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Our review paper on cosmic-ray processes in Galactic ecosystems is accepted by Galaxies.</title>
      <link>https://yoshiyukiinoue.github.io/post/2023-07-12-cr/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://yoshiyukiinoue.github.io/post/2023-07-12-cr/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Title: &lt;a href=&#34;https://arxiv.org/abs/2306.09924&#34;&gt;High energy emission component, population, and contribution to the extragalactic gamma-ray background of gamma-ray emitting radio galaxies&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;br&gt;&#xA;Authors: Ellis R. Owen, Kinwah Wu, Yoshiyuki Inoue, H.-Y. Karen Yang, Alison M. W. Mitchell&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Galaxy evolution is an important topic, and our physical understanding must be complete to establish a correct picture. This includes a thorough treatment of feedback. The effects of thermal-mechanical and radiative feedback have been widely considered, however cosmic rays (CRs) are also powerful energy carriers in galactic ecosystems. Resolving the capability of CRs to operate as a feedback agent is therefore essential to advance our understanding of the processes regulating galaxies. The effects of CRs are yet to be fully understood, and their complex multi-channel feedback mechanisms operating across the hierarchy of galaxy structures pose a significant technical challenge. This review examines the role of CRs in galaxies, from the scale of molecular clouds to the circum-galactic medium. An overview of their interaction processes, their implications for galaxy evolution, and their observable signatures is provided and their capability to modify the thermal and hydrodynamic configuration of galactic ecosystems is discussed. We present recent advancements in our understanding of CR processes and interpretation of their signatures, and highlight where technical challenges and unresolved questions persist. We discuss how these may be addressed with upcoming opportunities.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Our paper on the cm-mm radio spectrum of NGC 1068 is accepted by PASJ.</title>
      <link>https://yoshiyukiinoue.github.io/post/2023-06-26-ngc1068/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 Jun 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://yoshiyukiinoue.github.io/post/2023-06-26-ngc1068/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Title: &lt;a href=&#34;https://arxiv.org/abs/2306.15950&#34;&gt;The centimeter-to-submillimeter broad-band radio spectrum of the central compact component in a nearby type-II Seyfert galaxy NGC 1068&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;br&gt;&#xA;Authors: Tomonari Michiyama, Yoshiyuki Inoue, Akihiro Doi&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;We analyze all the available Atacama Large Millimeter / submillimeter Array archival data of the nearby Type-II Seyfert galaxy NGC 1068, including new 100 GHz data with the angular resolution of 0\farcs05, which was not included in previous continuum spectral analysis. By combining with the literature data based on the Very Large Array, we investigate the broadband radio continuum spectrum of the central ≲7 pc region of NGC 1068. We found that the flux density is between ≈10-20 mJy at 5-700 GHz. Due to the inability of the model in previous studies to account for the newly added 100 GHz data point, we proceeded to update the models and make the necessary adjustments to the parameters. One possible interpretation of this broadband radio spectrum is a combination of emission from the jet base, the dusty torus, and the compact X-raying corona with the magnetic field strength of ≈20 G on scales of ≈30 Schwarzschild radii from the central black hole. In order to firmly identify the compact corona by omitting any other possible extended components (e.g., free-free emission from ionized gas around), high-resolution/sensitivity observations achieved by next-generation interferometers will be necessary.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Our paper on the Zeeman effect in MAD is accepted by PASJ.</title>
      <link>https://yoshiyukiinoue.github.io/post/2023-02-28-zeeman/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://yoshiyukiinoue.github.io/post/2023-02-28-zeeman/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Title: &lt;a href=&#34;https://arxiv.org/abs/2302.14403&#34;&gt;On the Zeeman Effect in Magnetically-Arrested Disks&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;br&gt;&#xA;Authors: Yoshiyuki Inoue&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Magnetically arrested disk (MAD) has been argued as the key accretion phase to realize the formation of relativistic jets. However, due to the lack of magnetic field measurements of accreting systems, MAD has not been observationally confirmed yet. Here we propose that a strong magnetic field accompanied by MAD would induce the Zeeman splitting of relativistically broadened Fe Kα fluorescence lines in X-ray binaries and active galactic nuclei, where we consider a two-phase medium in the inner accretion disk, magnetically dominated hot corona and cold reflector. Such a geometrical configuration is suggested from X-ray observations and recently confirmed by numerical simulations. Although turbulence in accretion flows would broaden the split lines, future X-ray high-energy resolution satellites, XRISM and Athena, would be capable of seeing the Zeeman effect on the Fe lines in X-ray binaries in the case with the MAD configuration. The signature of the Zeeman split lines would provide observational evidence for MAD.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Our paper on the MeV source contribution to the inner Galactic Diffuse emission is accepted by ApJ.</title>
      <link>https://yoshiyukiinoue.github.io/post/2022-12-11-mevsourcediffuse/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://yoshiyukiinoue.github.io/post/2022-12-11-mevsourcediffuse/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Title: &lt;a href=&#34;https://arxiv.org/abs/2212.05713&#34;&gt;MeV Gamma-Ray Source Contribution to the Inner Galactic Diffuse Emission&#xA;&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;br&gt;&#xA;Authors: Naomi Tsuji, Yoshiyuki Inoue, Hiroki Yoneda, Reshmi Mukherjee, Hirokazu Odaka&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The origin of the inner Galactic emission, measured by COMPTEL with a flux of ∼10−2 MeV cm−2 s−1 sr−1 in the 1-30 MeV energy range from the inner Galactic region, has remained unsettled since its discovery. In this paper, we elaborate on a model of individual MeV gamma-ray sources unresolved by COMPTEL. This is conducted for sources crossmatched between the Swift-BAT and Fermi-LAT catalogs by interpolating the energy spectra in the hard X-ray and GeV gamma-ray ranges, as well as unmatched sources between the two catalogs. We find that the source contribution to the COMPTEL emission would be at least ~20%. Combined with the Galactic diffuse emission, which is not well constrained, the COMPTEL emission can be roughly reproduced in some cases.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Our paper on ALMA detection of pc-scale blobs at the head of kpc-scale jet in NGC 1068 by ApJL.</title>
      <link>https://yoshiyukiinoue.github.io/post/2022-08-12-ngc1068/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Aug 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://yoshiyukiinoue.github.io/post/2022-08-12-ngc1068/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Title: &lt;a href=&#34;https://arxiv.org/abs/2208.08533&#34;&gt;ALMA Detection of Parsec-scale Blobs at the Head of a Kiloparsec-scale Jet in the Nearby Seyfert Galaxy NGC 1068&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;br&gt;&#xA;Authors: Tomonari Michiyama, Yoshiyuki Inoue, Akihiro Doi, Dmitry Khangulyan&#xA;We present Atacama Large Millimeter/submillimeter Array observations at ≈100 GHz with 0.05 arcsec (3 pc) resolution of the kiloparsec-scale jet seen in the nearby Seyfert galaxy NGC 1068, and we report the presence of parsec-scale blobs at the head of the jet. The combination of the detected radio flux (≈0.8 mJy), spectral index (≈0.5), and the blob size (≈10 pc) suggests a strong magnetic field of B≈240μG. Such a strong magnetic field most likely implies magnetic field amplification by streaming cosmic rays. The estimated cosmic-ray power by the jet may exceed the limit set by the star formation activity in this galaxy. This result suggests that even modest-power jets can increase the galactic cosmic-ray content while propagating through the galactic bulge.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Our paper on the contribution of radio galaxies to the cosmic gamma-ray background radiation is accepted by ApJ.</title>
      <link>https://yoshiyukiinoue.github.io/post/2022-04-26-rg-cgb/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://yoshiyukiinoue.github.io/post/2022-04-26-rg-cgb/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Title: &lt;a href=&#34;https://arxiv.org/abs/2204.14019&#34;&gt;High energy emission component, population, and contribution to the extragalactic gamma-ray background of gamma-ray emitting radio galaxies&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;br&gt;&#xA;Authors: Yasushi Fukazawa, Hiroto Matake, Taishu Kayanoki, Yoshiyuki Inoue, Justin Finke&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In this study, we systematically studied the X-ray to GeV gamma-ray spectra of 61 {\it Fermi} Large Area Telescope (LAT) detected radio galaxies. We found an anticorrelation between peak frequency and peak luminosity in the high-energy spectral component of radio galaxies, similar to blazars. With this sample, we also constructed a gamma-ray luminosity function (GLF) of gamma-ray-loud radio galaxies. We found that blazar-like GLF shapes can reproduce their redshift and luminosity distribution, but the logN-logS relation prefers models with more low-z radio galaxies. This indicates many low-z gamma-ray-loud radio galaxies. By utilizing our latest GLF, the contribution of radio galaxies to the extragalactic gamma-ray background is found to be 1&amp;ndash;10%. We further investigated the nature of gamma-ray-loud radio galaxies. Compared to radio or X-ray flux-limited radio galaxy samples, the gamma-ray selected sample tends to lack high radio power galaxies like FR-II radio galaxies. We also found that only ∼10% of radio galaxies are GeV gamma-ray loud. Radio galaxies may contribute to the cosmic MeV gamma-ray background comparable to blazars if gamma-ray-quiet radio galaxies have X-ray to gamma-ray spectra like Cen A, with a small gamma-ray to X-ray flux ratio.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Our paper on interstellar gas heating by PBHs is accepted by JCAP.</title>
      <link>https://yoshiyukiinoue.github.io/post/2022-02-03-pbh-heating/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 03 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://yoshiyukiinoue.github.io/post/2022-02-03-pbh-heating/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Title: &lt;a href=&#34;https://arxiv.org/abs/2105.06099&#34;&gt;Interstellar Gas Heating by Primordial Black Holes&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;br&gt;&#xA;Authors: Volodymyr Takhistov, Philip Lu, Graciela B. Gelmini, Kohei Hayashi, Yoshiyuki Inoue, Alexander Kusenko&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Our paper on a fundamental plane in X-ray binary activity of external galaxies is accepted by PASJ.</title>
      <link>https://yoshiyukiinoue.github.io/post/2021-07-04-xrb-catalog/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 04 Jul 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://yoshiyukiinoue.github.io/post/2021-07-04-xrb-catalog/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Title: &lt;a href=&#34;https://arxiv.org/abs/2107.07775&#34;&gt;A fundamental plane in X-ray binary activity of external galaxies&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;br&gt;&#xA;Authors: Yoshiyuki Inoue, Kiyoto Yabe, Yoshihiro Ueda&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;We construct a new catalog of extragalactic X-ray binaries (XRBs) by matching the latest Chandra source catalog with local galaxy catalogs. Our XRB catalog contains 4430 XRBs hosted by 237 galaxies within $\sim130$ Mpc. As XRBs dominate the X-ray activity in galaxies, the catalog enables us to study the correlations between the total X-ray luminosity of a galaxy, star formation rate, and stellar mass. We find that there is a fundamental plane in those three parameters. In order to investigate this relation, we construct a phenomenological binary population synthesis model. We find that the high mass XRB and low mass XRB fraction in formed compact object binary systems is $\sim 9$% and $\sim0.04$%, respectively. Utilizing the latest XMM-Newton, and Swift X-ray source catalog data sets, additional XRB candidates are also found resulting in 5757 XRBs hosted by 311 galaxies.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Our paper on spatial variations of magnetic field along active galactic nuclei jets on sub-pc to Mpc scales is accepted by ApJ.</title>
      <link>https://yoshiyukiinoue.github.io/post/2021-06-03-agn-kpc/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 03 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://yoshiyukiinoue.github.io/post/2021-06-03-agn-kpc/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Title: &lt;a href=&#34;https://arxiv.org/abs/2106.01788&#34;&gt;Spatial variations of magnetic field along active galactic nuclei jets on sub-pc to Mpc scales&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;br&gt;&#xA;Authors: Soichiro Ito, Yoshiyuki Inoue, Jun Kataoka&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;We report the systematic analysis of knots, hotspots, and lobes in 57 active galactic nuclei (AGNs) to investigate the variation of the magnetic field along with the jet from the sub-pc base to the terminus in kpc-to-Mpc scales.   Expanding the number of radio/X-ray samples in \citet{2005ApJ&amp;hellip;622..797K}, we analyzed the data in 12 FR&lt;del&gt;I and 30 FR&lt;/del&gt;II radio galaxies, 12 quasars, and 3 BL Lacs that contained 76 knots, 42 hotspots, and 29 radio lobes.  We first derived the equipartition magnetic fields in the cores and then estimated those in various jet components by assuming $B_{\rm est}$ $\propto$ $d^{-1}$, where $d$ is the distance from the jet base. On the other hand, the magnetic field in large-scale jets (knots, hotspots, and lobes), $B_{\rm eq}$, can be estimated from the observed flux and spatial extent under the equipartition hypothesis.  We show that the magnetic field decreases as the distance along the jet increases, but generally gentler than $\propto d^{-1}$. The increase in $B_{\rm eq}/B_{\rm est}$ at a larger $d$ may suggest the deceleration of the jet around the downstream, but there is no difference between FR&lt;del&gt;I and FR&lt;/del&gt;II jets. Moreover, the magnetic fields in the hotspots are systematically larger than those of knots and lobes.  Finally, we applied the same analysis to knots and lobes in Centaurus~A to check whether  the above discussion will hold even in a {\it single} jet source.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Our paper on cross-match between the latest Swift-BAT and Fermi-LAT catalogs is accepted by ApJ.</title>
      <link>https://yoshiyukiinoue.github.io/post/2021-05-19-swift-fermi/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://yoshiyukiinoue.github.io/post/2021-05-19-swift-fermi/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Title: &lt;a href=&#34;https://arxiv.org/abs/2105.11791&#34;&gt;Cross-match between the latest Swift-BAT and Fermi-LAT catalogs&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;br&gt;&#xA;Authors: Naomi Tsuji, Hiroki Yoneda, Yoshiyuki Inoue, Tsuguo Aramaki, Georgia Karagiorgi, Reshmi Mukherjee, Hirokazu Odaka&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;We report the results of a cross-match study between the hard X-ray and GeV gamma-ray catalogs, by making use of the latest 105-month Swift-BAT and 10-yr Fermi-LAT catalogs, respectively. The spatial cross-matching between the two catalogs results in the matching of 132 point-like sources, including ~5% of false-match sources. Additionally, 24 sources that have been identified as the same identifications are matched. Among the 75 extended sources in the Fermi-LAT catalog, 31 sources have spatial coincidences with at least one Swift-BAT source inside their extent. All the matched sources consist of blazars (&amp;gt;60%), pulsars and pulsar wind nebulae (~13%), radio galaxies (~7%), binaries (~5%), and others. Compared to the original catalogs, the matched sources are characterized by a double-peaked photon index distribution, higher flux, and larger gamma-ray variability index. This difference arises from the different populations of sources, particularly the large proportion of blazars (i.e., FSRQ and BL Lac). We also report 13 cross-matched and unidentified sources. The matched sources in this study would be promising in the intermediate energy band between the hard X-ray and GeV gamma-ray observations, that is the unexplored MeV gamma-ray domain.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Our review article on the high energy aspect of AGN coronae is accepted by Galaxies.</title>
      <link>https://yoshiyukiinoue.github.io/post/2021-05-08-gamma-ray-neutrino-agn-corona/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 08 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://yoshiyukiinoue.github.io/post/2021-05-08-gamma-ray-neutrino-agn-corona/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Title: &lt;a href=&#34;https://arxiv.org/abs/2105.08948&#34;&gt;Gamma-ray and Neutrino Signals from Accretion Disk Coronae of Active Galactic Nuclei&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;br&gt;&#xA;Authors: Yoshiyuki Inoue, Dmitry Khangulyan, Akihiro Doi&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;To explain X-ray spectra of active galactic nuclei (AGN), non-thermal activity in AGN coronae such as pair cascade models has been extensively discussed in the past literature. Although X-ray and gamma-ray observations in the 1990s disfavored such pair cascade models, recent millimeter-wave observations of nearby Seyferts establish the existence of weak non-thermal coronal activity. Besides, the IceCube collaboration reported NGC 1068, a nearby Seyfert, as the hottest spot in their 10-yr survey. These pieces of evidence are enough to investigate the non-thermal perspective of AGN coronae in depth again. This article summarizes our current observational understandings of AGN coronae and describes how AGN coronae generate high-energy particles. We also provide ways to test the AGN corona model with radio, X-ray, MeV gamma-ray, and high-energy neutrino observations.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Our paper on the PBH abundance using Leo T is accepted by ApJL.</title>
      <link>https://yoshiyukiinoue.github.io/post/2021-01-15-pbh-leot/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://yoshiyukiinoue.github.io/post/2021-01-15-pbh-leot/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Title: &lt;a href=&#34;https://arxiv.org/abs/2007.02213&#34;&gt;Constraining Primordial Black Holes with Dwarf Galaxy Heating&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;br&gt;&#xA;Authors: Philip Lu, Volodymyr Takhistov, Graciela B. Gelmini, Kohei Hayashi, Yoshiyuki Inoue, Alexander Kusenko&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Black holes formed in the early universe, prior to the formation of stars, can exist as dark matter and also contribute to the black hole merger events observed in gravitational waves. We set a new limit on the abundance of primordial black holes (PBHs) by considering interactions of PBHs with the interstellar medium, which result in the heating of gas. We examine generic heating mechanisms, including emission from the accretion disk, dynamical friction, and disk outflows. Using the data from the Leo T dwarf galaxy, we set a new cosmology-independent limit on the abundance of PBHs in the mass range O(1)M_sun-10^7M_sun, relevant for the recently detected gravitational wave signals from intermediate-mass BHs.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Our paper on the origin of Galactic spurs is accepted by ApJ.</title>
      <link>https://yoshiyukiinoue.github.io/post/2021-01-07-galactic-spur/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 11 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://yoshiyukiinoue.github.io/post/2021-01-07-galactic-spur/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Title: &lt;a href=&#34;https://arxiv.org/abs/2101.03302&#34;&gt;Origin of Galactic Spurs: New Insight from Radio/X-ray All-sky Maps&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;br&gt;&#xA;Authors: Jun Kataoka, Marino Yamamoto, Yuki Nakamura, Soichiro Ito, Yoshiaki Sofue, Yoshiyuki Inoue, Takeshi Nakamori, Tomonori Totani&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In this study, we analyze giant Galactic spurs seen in both radio and X-ray all-sky maps to reveal their origins. We discuss two types of giant spurs: one is the brightest diffuse emission near the map&amp;rsquo;s center, which is likely to be related to Fermi bubbles (NPSs/SPSs, north/south polar spurs, respectively), and the other is weaker spurs that coincide positionally with local spiral arms in our Galaxy (LAS, local arm spur). Our analysis finds that the X-ray emissions, not only from the NPS but from the SPS are closer to the Galactic center by ~5 deg compared with the corresponding radio emission. Furthermore, larger offsets of 10-20 deg are observed in the LASs; however, they are attributed to different physical origins. Moreover, the temperature of the X-ray emission is kT ~ 0.2 keV for the LAS, which is systematically lower than those of the NPS and SPS (kT ~ 0.3 keV) but consistent with the typical temperature of Galactic halo gas. We argue that the radio/X-ray offset and the slightly higher temperature of the NPS/SPS X-ray gas are due to the shock compression/heating of halo gas during a significant Galactic explosion in the past, whereas the enhanced X-ray emission from the LAS may be due to the weak condensation of halo gas in the arm potential or star formation activity without shock heating.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Our paper on the optical follow-up of TXS 0506&#43;056 is accepted by PASJ.</title>
      <link>https://yoshiyukiinoue.github.io/post/2020-11-04-txs0506&#43;056/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Nov 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://yoshiyukiinoue.github.io/post/2020-11-04-txs0506&#43;056/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Title: &lt;a href=&#34;https://arxiv.org/abs/2011.04957&#34;&gt;Follow-up Observations for IceCube-170922A: Detection of Rapid Near-Infrared Variability and Intensive Monitoring of TXS 0506+056&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;br&gt;&#xA;Authors: Tomoki Morokuma, Yousuke Utsumi, Kouji Ohta, Masayuki Yamanaka, Koji S. Kawabata, Yoshiyuki Inoue, Masaomi Tanaka, Michitoshi Yoshida, Ryosuke Itoh, Mahito Sasada, Nozomu Tominaga, Hiroki Mori, Miho Kawabata, Tatsuya Nakaoka, Maiko Chogi, Taisei Abe, Ruochen Huang, Naoki Kawahara, Hiroki Kimura, Hiroki Nagashima, Kengo Takagi, Yuina Yamazaki, Wei Liu, Ryou Ohsawa, Shigeyuki Sako, Katsuhiro L. Murata, Kumiko Morihana, Christina K. Gilligan, Keisuke Isogai, Mariko Kimura, Yasuyuki Wakamatsu, Ryuhei Ohnishi, Masaki Takayama, Satoshi Honda, Yoshiki Matsuoka, Takuji Yamashita, Shigehiro Nagataki, Yasuyuki T. Tanaka&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>I join the theoretical astrophysics group at Osaka University as an associate professor</title>
      <link>https://yoshiyukiinoue.github.io/post/2020-09-16-osaka/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://yoshiyukiinoue.github.io/post/2020-09-16-osaka/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Our paper on the kiloparsec jet of Centaurus A is accepted by ApJL.</title>
      <link>https://yoshiyukiinoue.github.io/post/2020-08-26-cena/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Aug 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://yoshiyukiinoue.github.io/post/2020-08-26-cena/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Title: &lt;a href=&#34;https://arxiv.org/abs/2006.12519&#34;&gt;Physical Conditions and Particle Acceleration in the Kiloparsec Jet of Centaurus A&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;br&gt;&#xA;Authors: Takahiro Sudoh, Dmitry Khangulyan, Yoshiyuki Inoue&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The non-thermal emission from the kiloparsec-scale jet of Centaurus~A exhibits two notable features, bright diffuse emission and many compact knots, which have been intensively studied in X-ray and radio observations. H.E.S.S. recently reported that the very-high-energy gamma-ray emission from this object is extended along the jet direction beyond a kiloparsec from the core. Here, we combine these observations to constrain the physical conditions of the kpc-jet and study the origin of the non-thermal emission. We show that the diffuse jet is weakly magnetized ($\eta_B\sim10^{-2}$) and energetically dominated by thermal particles. We also show that knots are the sites of both amplified magnetic field and particle (re-)acceleration. To keep sufficient energy in thermal particles, the magnetic and non-thermal particle energy in the knot regions are tightly constrained. The most plausible condition is an energy equipartition between them, $\eta_B\sim\eta_e\sim0.1$. Such weak magnetic energy implies that particles in the knots are in the slow cooling regime. We suggest that the entire kpc-scale diffuse emission could be powered by particles that are accelerated at and escaped from knots.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Our new blazar catalog paper is accepted by ApJ.</title>
      <link>https://yoshiyukiinoue.github.io/post/2020-07-29-bros/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://yoshiyukiinoue.github.io/post/2020-07-29-bros/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Title: &lt;a href=&#34;https://arxiv.org/abs/2008.00038&#34;&gt;Blazar Radio and Optical Survey (BROS): A catalog of blazar candidates showing flat radio spectrum and their optical identification in Pan-STARRS1 Surveys&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;br&gt;&#xA;Authors: Ryosuke Itoh, Yousuke Utsumi, Yoshiyuki Inoue, Kouji Ohta, Akihiro Doi, Tomoki Morokuma, Koji S. Kawabata, Yasuyuki T. Tanaka&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Utilizing the latest and the most sensitive radio and optical catalogs, we completed a new blazar candidate catalog, Blazar Radio and Optical Survey (BROS), which includes 88,211 sources located at declination $\delta&amp;gt;−40^\circ$ and outside the galactic plane ($|b|&amp;gt;10^\circ$). We list compact flat-spectrum radio sources of $\aloha&amp;gt;−0.6$ from 0.15 GHz TGSS and 1.4 GHz NVSS catalogs. We further identify optical counterparts of the selected sources by cross-matching with Pan-STARRS1 photometric data.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Our paper on the evolution of FSRQs is accepted by ApJ.</title>
      <link>https://yoshiyukiinoue.github.io/post/2020-05-06-fsrq-xlf/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 06 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://yoshiyukiinoue.github.io/post/2020-05-06-fsrq-xlf/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Title: &lt;a href=&#34;https://arxiv.org/abs/2005.02648&#34;&gt;Cosmological Evolution of FSRQs based on the &lt;em&gt;Swift&lt;/em&gt;/BAT 105-month Catalog and Their Contribution to the Cosmic MeV Gamma-ray Background Radiation&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;br&gt;&#xA;Authors: Koyo Toda, Yasushi Fukazawa, Yoshiyuki Inoue&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;We present a new X-ray luminosity function of flat-spectrum radio quasars (FSRQs) utilizing the latest &lt;em&gt;Swift&lt;/em&gt;/BAT 105-month X-ray source catalog. Contrary to previous studies of FSRQs in the X-ray band, using the luminosity-dependent density evolution model, we find that FSRQs show evolutionary peaks at z∼1−2 depending on luminosities. Our result is rather consistent with the evolution of FSRQs seen in the radio and GeV bands, although the number density is a factor of 5&amp;ndash;10 smaller. We further explore the contribution of FSRQs to the cosmic MeV gamma-ray background radiation. We find that FSRQs can explain only ∼3% of the observed MeV gamma-ray background fluxes around 1 MeV, indicating other populations are required. Future MeV gamma-ray observations will be keys for understanding the origin of the MeV gamma-ray background radiation.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
