<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Yoshiyuki Inoue</title>
    <link>https://yoshiyukiinoue.github.io/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Yoshiyuki Inoue</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>ja</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 25 Mar 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://yoshiyukiinoue.github.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Graduation Day</title>
      <link>https://yoshiyukiinoue.github.io/post/2024-03-25-masterthesis/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Mar 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://yoshiyukiinoue.github.io/post/2024-03-25-masterthesis/</guid>
      <description>We are proud to announce the graduation of our esteemed students on March 25th, marking a significant milestone in their academic careers. Our master&amp;rsquo;s students, Kaoru Yanagisawa and Tomoya Yamada, were awarded their Master&amp;rsquo;s degrees, showcasing their exceptional skills and dedication in their respective fields of study. On the same day, our undergraduate student, Pan Yue, received her Bachelor&amp;rsquo;s degree, demonstrating her hard work and commitment to her studies.&#xA;Thesis titles:</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Dr. Samuel Barnier joined our group.</title>
      <link>https://yoshiyukiinoue.github.io/post/2023-04-01-dr.samuel-barnier/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Apr 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://yoshiyukiinoue.github.io/post/2023-04-01-dr.samuel-barnier/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Our group member, Tomonari Michiyama, is now an assistant professor at Shunan University .</title>
      <link>https://yoshiyukiinoue.github.io/post/2023-04-01-prof.tomonari-michiyama/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Apr 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://yoshiyukiinoue.github.io/post/2023-04-01-prof.tomonari-michiyama/</guid>
      <description>(URL)</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Bachelor Thesis Presentation Day</title>
      <link>https://yoshiyukiinoue.github.io/post/2023-02-13-bachelor/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://yoshiyukiinoue.github.io/post/2023-02-13-bachelor/</guid>
      <description>We are pleasure to hear that two excellent undergraduate students in our group defended their bachelor thesis presentations. Katsunori Kusakabe looked into the stellar magnetic field condition to realize the magnetically arrested disk in X-ray binaries. Tatsuki Fujiwara worked on 26Al gamma-ray line signals from solar bodies as well as the estimation of past cosmic-ray activity using comets. Congratulations to all of them!</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Dr. Ellis R. Owen joined our group.</title>
      <link>https://yoshiyukiinoue.github.io/post/2022-11-28-dr.ellis-owen/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 28 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://yoshiyukiinoue.github.io/post/2022-11-28-dr.ellis-owen/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Our paper on the contribution of radio galaxies to the cosmic gamma-ray background radiation is accepted by ApJ.</title>
      <link>https://yoshiyukiinoue.github.io/post/2022-04-26-rg-cgb/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://yoshiyukiinoue.github.io/post/2022-04-26-rg-cgb/</guid>
      <description>Title: High energy emission component, population, and contribution to the extragalactic gamma-ray background of gamma-ray emitting radio galaxies.&#xA;Authors: Yasushi Fukazawa, Hiroto Matake, Taishu Kayanoki, Yoshiyuki Inoue, Justin Finke&#xA;In this study, we systematically studied the X-ray to GeV gamma-ray spectra of 61 {\it Fermi} Large Area Telescope (LAT) detected radio galaxies. We found an anticorrelation between peak frequency and peak luminosity in the high-energy spectral component of radio galaxies, similar to blazars.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Our Group Member, Naomi Tsuji, is now an assistant professor at Kanagawa University .</title>
      <link>https://yoshiyukiinoue.github.io/post/2022-04-01-prof.naomi-tsuji/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://yoshiyukiinoue.github.io/post/2022-04-01-prof.naomi-tsuji/</guid>
      <description>(URL)</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Bachelor Thesis Presentation Day</title>
      <link>https://yoshiyukiinoue.github.io/post/2022-02-16-bachelor/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://yoshiyukiinoue.github.io/post/2022-02-16-bachelor/</guid>
      <description>We are pleasure to hear that our excellent undergraduate student defended his bachelor thesis presentation. Tomoya Yamada worked on radio emission signals from AGN disk winds. Congratulations!</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Our paper on interstellar gas heating by PBHs is accepted by JCAP.</title>
      <link>https://yoshiyukiinoue.github.io/post/2022-02-03-pbh-heating/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 03 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://yoshiyukiinoue.github.io/post/2022-02-03-pbh-heating/</guid>
      <description>Title: Interstellar Gas Heating by Primordial Black Holes.&#xA;Authors: Volodymyr Takhistov, Philip Lu, Graciela B. Gelmini, Kohei Hayashi, Yoshiyuki Inoue, Alexander Kusenko</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Our paper on a fundamental plane in X-ray binary activity of external galaxies is accepted by PASJ.</title>
      <link>https://yoshiyukiinoue.github.io/post/2021-07-04-xrb-catalog/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 04 Jul 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://yoshiyukiinoue.github.io/post/2021-07-04-xrb-catalog/</guid>
      <description>Title: A fundamental plane in X-ray binary activity of external galaxies.&#xA;Authors: Yoshiyuki Inoue, Kiyoto Yabe, Yoshihiro Ueda&#xA;We construct a new catalog of extragalactic X-ray binaries (XRBs) by matching the latest Chandra source catalog with local galaxy catalogs. Our XRB catalog contains 4430 XRBs hosted by 237 galaxies within $\sim130$ Mpc. As XRBs dominate the X-ray activity in galaxies, the catalog enables us to study the correlations between the total X-ray luminosity of a galaxy, star formation rate, and stellar mass.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Our paper on spatial variations of magnetic field along active galactic nuclei jets on sub-pc to Mpc scales is accepted by ApJ.</title>
      <link>https://yoshiyukiinoue.github.io/post/2021-06-03-agn-kpc/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 03 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://yoshiyukiinoue.github.io/post/2021-06-03-agn-kpc/</guid>
      <description>Title: Spatial variations of magnetic field along active galactic nuclei jets on sub-pc to Mpc scales.&#xA;Authors: Soichiro Ito, Yoshiyuki Inoue, Jun Kataoka&#xA;We report the systematic analysis of knots, hotspots, and lobes in 57 active galactic nuclei (AGNs) to investigate the variation of the magnetic field along with the jet from the sub-pc base to the terminus in kpc-to-Mpc scales. Expanding the number of radio/X-ray samples in \citet{2005ApJ&amp;hellip;622..797K}, we analyzed the data in 12 FR~I and 30 FR~II radio galaxies, 12 quasars, and 3 BL Lacs that contained 76 knots, 42 hotspots, and 29 radio lobes.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Our paper on cross-match between the latest Swift-BAT and Fermi-LAT catalogs is accepted by ApJ.</title>
      <link>https://yoshiyukiinoue.github.io/post/2021-05-19-swift-fermi/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://yoshiyukiinoue.github.io/post/2021-05-19-swift-fermi/</guid>
      <description>Title: Cross-match between the latest Swift-BAT and Fermi-LAT catalogs.&#xA;Authors: Naomi Tsuji, Hiroki Yoneda, Yoshiyuki Inoue, Tsuguo Aramaki, Georgia Karagiorgi, Reshmi Mukherjee, Hirokazu Odaka&#xA;We report the results of a cross-match study between the hard X-ray and GeV gamma-ray catalogs, by making use of the latest 105-month Swift-BAT and 10-yr Fermi-LAT catalogs, respectively. The spatial cross-matching between the two catalogs results in the matching of 132 point-like sources, including ~5% of false-match sources.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Our review article on the high energy aspect of AGN coronae is accepted by Galaxies.</title>
      <link>https://yoshiyukiinoue.github.io/post/2021-05-08-gamma-ray-neutrino-agn-corona/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 08 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://yoshiyukiinoue.github.io/post/2021-05-08-gamma-ray-neutrino-agn-corona/</guid>
      <description>Title: Gamma-ray and Neutrino Signals from Accretion Disk Coronae of Active Galactic Nuclei.&#xA;Authors: Yoshiyuki Inoue, Dmitry Khangulyan, Akihiro Doi&#xA;To explain X-ray spectra of active galactic nuclei (AGN), non-thermal activity in AGN coronae such as pair cascade models has been extensively discussed in the past literature. Although X-ray and gamma-ray observations in the 1990s disfavored such pair cascade models, recent millimeter-wave observations of nearby Seyferts establish the existence of weak non-thermal coronal activity.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Dr. Tomonari Michiyama joined our group.</title>
      <link>https://yoshiyukiinoue.github.io/post/2021-04-01-dr.tomonari-michiyama/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://yoshiyukiinoue.github.io/post/2021-04-01-dr.tomonari-michiyama/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Bachelor Thesis Presentation Day</title>
      <link>https://yoshiyukiinoue.github.io/post/2021-02-06-bachelor/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 06 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://yoshiyukiinoue.github.io/post/2021-02-06-bachelor/</guid>
      <description>We are pleasure to hear that our excellent undergraduate student defended his bachelor thesis presentation. Kaoru Yanagisawa worked on new PBH constraint method using AGN torus. Congratulations!</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Our paper on the PBH abundance using Leo T is accepted by ApJL.</title>
      <link>https://yoshiyukiinoue.github.io/post/2021-01-15-pbh-leot/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://yoshiyukiinoue.github.io/post/2021-01-15-pbh-leot/</guid>
      <description>Title: Constraining Primordial Black Holes with Dwarf Galaxy Heating.&#xA;Authors: Philip Lu, Volodymyr Takhistov, Graciela B. Gelmini, Kohei Hayashi, Yoshiyuki Inoue, Alexander Kusenko&#xA;Black holes formed in the early universe, prior to the formation of stars, can exist as dark matter and also contribute to the black hole merger events observed in gravitational waves. We set a new limit on the abundance of primordial black holes (PBHs) by considering interactions of PBHs with the interstellar medium, which result in the heating of gas.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Our paper on the origin of Galactic spurs is accepted by ApJ.</title>
      <link>https://yoshiyukiinoue.github.io/post/2021-01-07-galactic-spur/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 11 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://yoshiyukiinoue.github.io/post/2021-01-07-galactic-spur/</guid>
      <description>Title: Origin of Galactic Spurs: New Insight from Radio/X-ray All-sky Maps.&#xA;Authors: Jun Kataoka, Marino Yamamoto, Yuki Nakamura, Soichiro Ito, Yoshiaki Sofue, Yoshiyuki Inoue, Takeshi Nakamori, Tomonori Totani&#xA;In this study, we analyze giant Galactic spurs seen in both radio and X-ray all-sky maps to reveal their origins. We discuss two types of giant spurs: one is the brightest diffuse emission near the map&amp;rsquo;s center, which is likely to be related to Fermi bubbles (NPSs/SPSs, north/south polar spurs, respectively), and the other is weaker spurs that coincide positionally with local spiral arms in our Galaxy (LAS, local arm spur).</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Our paper on the optical follow-up of TXS 0506&#43;056 is accepted by PASJ.</title>
      <link>https://yoshiyukiinoue.github.io/post/2020-11-04-txs0506&#43;056/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Nov 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://yoshiyukiinoue.github.io/post/2020-11-04-txs0506&#43;056/</guid>
      <description>Title: Follow-up Observations for IceCube-170922A: Detection of Rapid Near-Infrared Variability and Intensive Monitoring of TXS 0506+056.&#xA;Authors: Tomoki Morokuma, Yousuke Utsumi, Kouji Ohta, Masayuki Yamanaka, Koji S. Kawabata, Yoshiyuki Inoue, Masaomi Tanaka, Michitoshi Yoshida, Ryosuke Itoh, Mahito Sasada, Nozomu Tominaga, Hiroki Mori, Miho Kawabata, Tatsuya Nakaoka, Maiko Chogi, Taisei Abe, Ruochen Huang, Naoki Kawahara, Hiroki Kimura, Hiroki Nagashima, Kengo Takagi, Yuina Yamazaki, Wei Liu, Ryou Ohsawa, Shigeyuki Sako, Katsuhiro L. Murata, Kumiko Morihana, Christina K.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Postdoctoral Researcher Position at Osaka University</title>
      <link>https://yoshiyukiinoue.github.io/post/2020-10-05-alma_pd/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://yoshiyukiinoue.github.io/post/2020-10-05-alma_pd/</guid>
      <description>Now I am seeking a postdoctoral researcher at Osaka University. The candidate will work on the study of AGN coronal emission using theory, X-ray data, and radio (ALMA) data.&#xA;The position is posted here: https://jobregister.aas.org/ad/c9248b30&#xA;Application Deadline: Friday, November 13, 2020&#xA;活動銀河核コロナの研究に関する特任研究員(理論 and/or 観測)を一名、公募しております。 応募締切は令和2年11月13日(金) 日本時間 15:00必着です。 国立天文台で雇用され、大阪大学(豊中キャンパス)に派遣される形になります。&#xA;詳しくはこちらをご参照ください。 https://jobregister.nao.ac.jp/ja-JP/jobVacancyList https://www.nao.ac.jp/contents/job-vacancy/job-20201012-alma-osaka.pdf&#xA;興味のある方々からの積極的なご応募をお待ちしております。&#xA;質問等あれば、お気軽にお問い合わせください。</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>I join the theoretical astrophysics group at Osaka University as an associate professor</title>
      <link>https://yoshiyukiinoue.github.io/post/2020-09-16-osaka/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://yoshiyukiinoue.github.io/post/2020-09-16-osaka/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Our paper on the kiloparsec jet of Centaurus A is accepted by ApJL.</title>
      <link>https://yoshiyukiinoue.github.io/post/2020-08-26-cena/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Aug 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://yoshiyukiinoue.github.io/post/2020-08-26-cena/</guid>
      <description>Title: Physical Conditions and Particle Acceleration in the Kiloparsec Jet of Centaurus A.&#xA;Authors: Takahiro Sudoh, Dmitry Khangulyan, Yoshiyuki Inoue&#xA;The non-thermal emission from the kiloparsec-scale jet of Centaurus~A exhibits two notable features, bright diffuse emission and many compact knots, which have been intensively studied in X-ray and radio observations. H.E.S.S. recently reported that the very-high-energy gamma-ray emission from this object is extended along the jet direction beyond a kiloparsec from the core.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A public talk at the Asahi Culture Center in Shinjuku</title>
      <link>https://yoshiyukiinoue.github.io/post/2020-08-22-asahi_culture/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 22 Aug 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://yoshiyukiinoue.github.io/post/2020-08-22-asahi_culture/</guid>
      <description>朝日カルチャーセンター新宿教室の「宇宙の爆発現象シリーズ」第4回において、「巨大ブラックホールを通して紐解く宇宙の歴史」というタイトルで話しました。</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Our new blazar catalog paper is accepted by ApJ.</title>
      <link>https://yoshiyukiinoue.github.io/post/2020-07-29-bros/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://yoshiyukiinoue.github.io/post/2020-07-29-bros/</guid>
      <description>Title: Blazar Radio and Optical Survey (BROS): A catalog of blazar candidates showing flat radio spectrum and their optical identification in Pan-STARRS1 Surveys.&#xA;Authors: Ryosuke Itoh, Yousuke Utsumi, Yoshiyuki Inoue, Kouji Ohta, Akihiro Doi, Tomoki Morokuma, Koji S. Kawabata, Yasuyuki T. Tanaka&#xA;Utilizing the latest and the most sensitive radio and optical catalogs, we completed a new blazar candidate catalog, Blazar Radio and Optical Survey (BROS), which includes 88,211 sources located at declination $\delta&amp;gt;−40^\circ$ and outside the galactic plane ($|b|&amp;gt;10^\circ$).</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Renovate my website</title>
      <link>https://yoshiyukiinoue.github.io/post/2020-05-27-renovation-webpage/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://yoshiyukiinoue.github.io/post/2020-05-27-renovation-webpage/</guid>
      <description>I renovate my website. Now it relys on Hugo. I adopt the Beautiful Hugo as the theme.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Our paper on the evolution of FSRQs is accepted by ApJ.</title>
      <link>https://yoshiyukiinoue.github.io/post/2020-05-06-fsrq-xlf/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 06 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://yoshiyukiinoue.github.io/post/2020-05-06-fsrq-xlf/</guid>
      <description>Title: Cosmological Evolution of FSRQs based on the Swift/BAT 105-month Catalog and Their Contribution to the Cosmic MeV Gamma-ray Background Radiation.&#xA;Authors: Koyo Toda, Yasushi Fukazawa, Yoshiyuki Inoue&#xA;We present a new X-ray luminosity function of flat-spectrum radio quasars (FSRQs) utilizing the latest Swift/BAT 105-month X-ray source catalog. Contrary to previous studies of FSRQs in the X-ray band, using the luminosity-dependent density evolution model, we find that FSRQs show evolutionary peaks at z∼1−2 depending on luminosities.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A lecture talk at University of Tokyo</title>
      <link>https://yoshiyukiinoue.github.io/post/2020-04-22-lecture/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://yoshiyukiinoue.github.io/post/2020-04-22-lecture/</guid>
      <description>東大駒場の2020年度学術フロンティア講義「数理科学の研究フロンティア：宇宙，物質，生命，情報」において、「ブラックホールを通して紐解く宇宙の歴史」というタイトルで講義をしました。スライドはこちらから。</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Dr. Naomi Tsuji joined our group.</title>
      <link>https://yoshiyukiinoue.github.io/post/2020-04-01-dr.naomi-tsuji/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://yoshiyukiinoue.github.io/post/2020-04-01-dr.naomi-tsuji/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://yoshiyukiinoue.github.io/page/exrbcatalog/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://yoshiyukiinoue.github.io/page/exrbcatalog/</guid>
      <description>Extragalactic X-ray Binary Catalog Extragalactic X-ray Binary Catalog described in Inoue, Yabe, &amp;amp; Ueda 2021 PASJ&#xA;Introduction We construct a new catalog of extragalactic X-ray binaries (XRBs) utilizing the latest Chandra, XMM-Newton, and Swift X-ray source catalogs by matching with the local galaxy catalogs. Our fiducial catalog including Chandra sources only contains 4430 XRBs hosted by 237 galaxies within ~130 Mpc. Utilizing the latest XMM-Newton, and Swift X-ray source catalog data sets, additional XRB candidates are also found resulting in 5757 XRBs hosted by 311 galaxies.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Downloads</title>
      <link>https://yoshiyukiinoue.github.io/page/download/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://yoshiyukiinoue.github.io/page/download/</guid>
      <description>Data from our papers Please read each paper for details. To download numerical data, please click the link right next to the &amp;ldquo;Data File:&amp;rdquo;. If you have any queries and/or need other data, please contact me freely.&#xA;Extragalactic Background Light model: (Inoue et al. 2013)&#xA;Model data of EBL intensity (z=0), Proper photon density, and Gamma-ray Opacity Data File: EBL_data_yinoue.tar.gz A bound on primordial black holes density: (Inoue &amp;amp; Kusenko 2017)</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Lecture</title>
      <link>https://yoshiyukiinoue.github.io/page/lecture/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://yoshiyukiinoue.github.io/page/lecture/</guid>
      <description>Lecture/講義関係 2024 力学2 (CLE 参照) 力学2 演義 (CLE 参照) 広島大学集中講義 (Password Required) Lecture 1, Lecture 2, Lecture 3, Lecture 4, Lecture 5, Lecture 6, Lecture 7, Lecture 8, Lecture 9 2023 力学2 (CLE 参照) 力学2 演義 (CLE 参照) 高エネルギー天文学 (CLE 参照) Chiba University Intensive Lecture (Password Required) Lecture 1, Lecture 2, Lecture 3, Lecture 4, Lecture 5, Lecture 6, Lecture 7, Note 2022 力学2 (CLE 参照) 力学2 演義 (CLE 参照) 先端物理学・宇宙地球科学輪講 (CLE 参照) 2021 力学2 (CLE 参照) 力学2 演義 (CLE 参照) 高エネルギー天文学 (CLE 参照) 先端物理学・宇宙地球科学輪講 (CLE 参照) </description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Profile</title>
      <link>https://yoshiyukiinoue.github.io/page/profile/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://yoshiyukiinoue.github.io/page/profile/</guid>
      <description>Profile Name / 名前: Yoshiyuki Inoue / 井上　芳幸&#xA;Email: yinoue_at_astro-osaka.jp Research Fields: High Energy Astrophysics, Black Holes, Active Galactic Nuclei, Relativistic Jets, Cosmic Background Radiation&#xA;Missions: CTA (2010-), Fermi (2012-), Hitomi (2012-), NuSTAR (2012-2014), MAGIC (2019-), GRAMS (2019-)&#xA;Degrees Ph.D., Kyoto University, March 2012 M.Sc.,Kyoto University, March 2009 B.Sc.,Kyoto University, March 2007 Takatsuki High School / 高槻高校, March 2003 Positions 客員主管研究員, 理化学研究所数理創造プログラム (09/2020-) 客員科学研究員, Kavli IPMU (07/2018-) 大阪大学大学院理学研究科 准教授 (2020年9月16日〜現在) 理化学研究所数理創造プログラム&#x9;上級研究員 (2017年11月 &amp;ndash; 2020年9月15日) JAXA国際トップヤングフェロー、宇宙航空研究開発機構/宇宙科学研究所（2014年2月 &amp;ndash; 2017年10月) 日本学術振興会海外研究員、KIPAC/SLAC国立加速器研究所/スタンフォード大学 (2012年4月 &amp;ndash; 2014年1月) 日本学術振興会特別研究員、京都大学（2009年4月 &amp;ndash; 2012年3月) Awards 2017年度日本天文学会研究奨励賞 Grants NASA APRA Proposal (Co-I), US$6,418,218, FY2023 &amp;ndash; 2026</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Talks Before 2020</title>
      <link>https://yoshiyukiinoue.github.io/page/talk_before2020/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://yoshiyukiinoue.github.io/page/talk_before2020/</guid>
      <description>Not Complete Invited Gordon Research Conference &#34;New Tools for the Next Generation of Particle Physics and Cosmology&#34;, Hong Kong, July 2019&#xA;&#34;Gamma-ray Astrophysics: Phenomenology&#34; The 10th International workshop on Very High Energy Particle Astronomy (VHEPA2019), Kashiwa, February 2019&#xA;&#34;Multi-messenger Signals from Supermassive Black Holes&#34; The fifth Physics and Astrophysics at the Extreme PAX V-MM19 workshop, USA, Febrary 2019&#xA;“Power of AGN Jets” Accretion Processes in Cosmic Sources - II, Russia, September 2018</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Team Members</title>
      <link>https://yoshiyukiinoue.github.io/page/members/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://yoshiyukiinoue.github.io/page/members/</guid>
      <description>Current Members Name Position Samuel Barnier JSPS Fellow Tatsuki Fujiwara Graduate Student Yoshiyuki Inoue Associate Professor Katsunori Kusakabe Graduate Student Ellis R. Owen JSPS Fellow Nobuyuki Sakai Graduate Student Alumni Name Past Position Current Position Nagisa Hiroshima RIKEN iTHEMS PD Associate Professor @ Yokohama National University Naomi Tsuji RIKEN iTHEMS PD Assistant Professor @ Kanagawa University Tomonari Michiyama ALMA PD Assistant Professor @ Shunan University Kaoru Yanagisawa Graduate Student Private company Tomoya Yamada Graduate Student Private company </description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>学生のみなさんへ</title>
      <link>https://yoshiyukiinoue.github.io/page/forstudents/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://yoshiyukiinoue.github.io/page/forstudents/</guid>
      <description>学生のみなさんに伝えておきたいことを、雑多にまとめました。長くなったので、忙しい人は読まないほうが良いです。&#xA;健康管理 無事之名馬。 倒れたら研究はできません。規則正しい生活・適度な息抜きは大切です。オン・オフの切替も大事です。研究より自分と家族を大切に1。 教育・研究方針について 僕の基本方針は東大の戸谷さんのページにあるとおりです2。&#xA;戸谷研 学生心得 追加コメント。&#xA;理論天文学において、(任期あり)若手研究者が新たに(任期なし)常勤ポストにつく数は大体4〜5名/年とありますが、データが少し古いです。運営費交付金削減の影響などで、現在はもう少し減っています。数名/年ぐらいの心づもりが良いと思います。一方で、毎年10名ほどの博士号取得者が研究にすすんでいます。つまり、需要と供給が釣り合っておらず、任期なしポストは苛烈な競争下にあります。寒い時代ですが、この状況で生き抜くしかありません。各所での面接候補者リストなどをみると、少なくとも ±5 学年の人と職を争うことになります。つまり M1 は D3 に追いつかないといけない。この苛烈な競争環境を生き抜くには、最低5年分を埋める・追い越す努力、または突き放す努力が必要でしょう。 考える力を養おう。 研究≠勉強 自分で考える力が大事です。 そのためには、色んな人と議論する。いろんな論文を読む。新しいアイデアを考える3。他の人の研究のいいところ・改善すべきところを勝手に考える。などなど、常に考えることです。 良くない例：「こういう結果がでました。」「なんでこうなったの？」「計算したらそうなりました。」「なんで&amp;hellip;(終)」 良い例：「こういう結果がでました。」「なんでこうなったの？」「Klein-Nishina の影響で、こうなりました。」「なるほど。でも、それだったら&amp;hellip;(続)」 なぜその結果が得られたのか。立ち止まって、考えましょう。 考えることを放棄して、他人任せにしてはいけないのです。 間違ってもいい。間違わない人なんていません。人と議論して、考えることで、正解に近づいていける。はず。 書類の準備について 学振などの重要書類は、締切の２週間前には仕上げておく。 締切直前に申請書類を回覧しても、 他の人が読めない。→コメントも取り込めない。→審査員の気持ちになって読み直す時間もない。→クォリティが低い。→採用率下がる。 余裕をもって申請書類を回覧すると、 他の人が読める。→コメントも取り込める。→審査員の気持ちになって読み直せる。→クォリティが高くなる。→採用率上がる。 僕は休日に仕事しないので、金曜夜に書類を持ってきても、月曜以降にしか読めません。 戦力の分散投資のすすめ (PD以上) リスクヘッジを取る。一つの分野だけに集中していると、その分野でトップにならないといけない。容易ではない。職が出るかも、時の運次第。 観測プロジェクトと深く関わっている理論家の場合、想定通りプロジェクトが進まなかったら、一本槍の理論家はどうしますか？ 大学院生のときは、自分の研究分野で足を固めることが大事かと思います。国際会議で招待講演に呼ばれるぐらいになるのが理想。 しかし、PD になったら、分野の幅を広げてみる。他のことにも挑戦してみる。 物理は一緒。天文学の面白いところは広範な物理の知識が必要なことです。逆に言えば、天文学の中で分野を変えるのは可能ということです。 論文執筆について 東大・祖父江さんの 「論文：千年残る究極のプレゼン道」は必読。&#xA;研究者の最低限の仕事は論文を書くこと。&#xA;論文を書くことは当たり前。&#xA;昔聞いたありがたいお言葉&#xA;PD &amp;ldquo;OK. I have to work!&amp;rdquo;&#xA;Professor &amp;ldquo;No! You have to produce!&amp;rdquo;&#xA;仕事(研究)をするだけではなく、論文を書くのである。&#xA;とはいえ、僕自身は沢山論文を書いている部類ではありません。。みなさん、頑張りましょう。&#xA;セミナーの準備の仕方について 東大・河東さん(数学)のページが非常に良い参考になると思います。このぐらいの心構えは必要かもしれない。僕自身、正直ここまでできな 質問について 若いうちはとにかく質問をする。アホな質問はしていい。よくよく聞いていると、偉い(とされている)人たちも結構しょうもない質問をしている。 昔聞いたありがたいお言葉&#xA;「アホな質問なんてなくてね、回答が質問をアホにするかを決めるんや。」 ただし、セミナーなどで、何度も発表を遮って、発表の邪魔をするのは良くない。 僕自身、D2 の頃に不規則な生活を続けていたら、(ストレスで)帯状疱疹になった経験があります。&amp;#160;&amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>研究紹介</title>
      <link>https://yoshiyukiinoue.github.io/page/research/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://yoshiyukiinoue.github.io/page/research/</guid>
      <description>研究スタイル 私は理論・観測の手段を問わずに研究を進めています。興味があれば何でもやってみようという研究スタンスです。&#xA;主な研究対象 ブラックホール天体 天体現象としては、ブラックホール天体が好きです。ブラックホール天体といっても原始ブラックホールから巨大ブラックホール、降着円盤やジェットなど様々な研究テーマが挙げられますが、基本的にブラックホール関係は天体物理現象であれば、どの分野にも興味があります。&#xA;MeV ガンマ線天文学 重力波観測も可能となった現代天文学ですが、MeVガンマ線領域はその観測の窓が閉ざされています。そこで、MeVガンマ線天文学を切り拓くため、Gamma-Ray and AntiMatter Survey (GRAMS) 実験を推進しています。GRAMS は MeV ガンマ線だけでなく反粒子検出によるダークマター間接探索も行う実験計画です。&#xA;詳しい研究内容は論文リストなどを参照してください。</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>発表リスト</title>
      <link>https://yoshiyukiinoue.github.io/page/talk/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://yoshiyukiinoue.github.io/page/talk/</guid>
      <description>Previous Talks: Before 2020, 2020, 2021, 2022&#xA;2024 Title: TBD Date: 2024/4/22-26 Place: International Conference on High Energy Density Sciences 2024, Yokohama, Japan Presentation: Talk 2023 Title: &#34;Non-thermal Coronal Activity in Seyfert Galaxies&#34; Date: 2023/11/14 Place: Chiba University, Chiba, Japan Presentation: Seminar Title: &#34;Intensive Lecture: High Energy Astrophysics&#34; Date: 2023/11/13-15 Place: Chiba University, Chiba, Japan Presentation: Intensive Lecture Title: &#34;High-Energy Accretion Phenomena Around Black Holes&#34; Date: 2023/08/10-11 Place: RESCEU Summer School 2023, Nagano, Japan Presentation: Intensive Lecture Title: &#34;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>発表リスト</title>
      <link>https://yoshiyukiinoue.github.io/page/talk_2020/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://yoshiyukiinoue.github.io/page/talk_2020/</guid>
      <description>Previous Talks: Before 2020, 2020, 2021, 2022&#xA;2020 Title: &#34;Coronal Magnetic Activity in nearby Active Supermassive Black Holes&#34; Date: 2020/12/18 Place: ICRR Seminar, zoom Presentation: Talk (pdf) Title: &#34;Future Prospects of MeV Gamma-ray Astronomy&#34; Date: 2020/12/07-10 Place: Connecting high-energy astroparticle physics for origins of cosmic rays and future perspectives, zoom or Kyoto Presentation: Talk (pdf) Title: &#34;ブラックホールの探し方&#34; Date: 2020/12/06 Place: iTHEMS x academist オンラインイベント, zoom Presentation: Lecture Title: &#34;ブラックホールを通して紐解く宇宙の歴史&#34; Date: 2020/12/04 Place: 先端物理学・宇宙地球科学輪講, zoom Presentation: Lecture Title: &#34;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>発表リスト</title>
      <link>https://yoshiyukiinoue.github.io/page/talk_2021/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://yoshiyukiinoue.github.io/page/talk_2021/</guid>
      <description>Previous Talks: Before 2020, 2020, 2021, 2022&#xA;2021 Title: &#34;Coronal Magnetic Activity in nearby Active Supermassive Black Holes&#34; Date: 2021/12/16 Place: AP Seminar @ Kyoto University, Kyoto Presentation: Talk (pdf) Title: &#34;宇宙とブラックホール&#34; Date: 2021/12/21 Place: Social Solution Initiative Workshop, zoom Presentation: Talk Title: &#34;How can we find black holes&#34; Date: 2021/03/15 Place: NTHU Astronomy Winter School, zoom Presentation: Talk (pdf) Title: &#34;Cosmological aspects of high energy astrophysics&#34; Date: 2021/01/18-22 Place: NTHU Astronomy Winter School, zoom and Hsinchu, Taiwan Presentation: Lecture (pdf) Title: &#34;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>発表リスト</title>
      <link>https://yoshiyukiinoue.github.io/page/talk_2022/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://yoshiyukiinoue.github.io/page/talk_2022/</guid>
      <description>Previous Talks: Before 2020, 2020, 2021, 2022&#xA;2022 Title: &#34;Unjetted AGNs as Neutrino Sources&#34; Date: 2022/09/20 Place: KM3NeT Town Hall Meeting, zoom Presentation: Talk Title: &#34;ブラックホールの探し方&#34; Date: 2022/09/06 Place: 千里ライフサイエンスフォーラム, 公益財団法人　千里ライフサイエンス振興財団, 千里ライフサイエンスセンタービル Presentation: Talk Title: &#34;Coronal magnetic activity in nearby active supermassive black holes&#34; Date: 2022/08/22 Place: 15th Asia Pacific Physics Conference (APPC15), zoom Presentation: Talk Title: &#34;ブラックホールの探し方&#34; Date: 2022/08/08 Place: 2022年度第14回高校生事業「研究者と語ろう」, 公益財団法人　千里ライフサイエンス振興財団, 大阪大学吹田キャンパス Presentation: Talk Title: &#34;Multi-Messenger Signals from Unjetted Active Supermassive Black Holes&#34;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>論文リスト</title>
      <link>https://yoshiyukiinoue.github.io/page/publication/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://yoshiyukiinoue.github.io/page/publication/</guid>
      <description>List of Papers NASA/ADS All Papers First Author Papers Observational Proposals (Not Complete) PI programs Unveiling Local Metallicity Environment of X-ray Binaries in M 51&#xA;PI: Yoshiyuki Inoue, Seimei 2020A, 3 nights Search for time variability in coronal syncrotron emission in a nearby Seyfert galaxy&#xA;PI: Yoshiyuki Inoue, ALMA Cycle-7 Unveiling Local Metallicity Environment of X-ray Binaries in M 33&#xA;PI: Yoshiyuki Inoue, Seimei 2019B, 4 nights Unveiling Local Metallicity Environment of X-ray Binaries in M 51</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
